import { Exercise } from ".";

export const COLORS: Exercise[] = [
  {
    "question": "красный",
    "answer": "krasnyj",
    "extra": "🔴"
  },
  {
    "question": "синий",
    "answer": "sinij",
    "extra": "🔵"
  },
  {
    "question": "зелёный",
    "answer": "ziel´onyj",
    "extra": "🟢"
  },
  {
    "question": "жёлтый",
    "answer": "żołtyj",
    "extra": "🟡"
  },
  {
    "question": "оранжевый",
    "answer": "oranzewyj",
    "extra": "🟠"
  },
  {
    "question": "розовый",
    "answer": "rozowyj",
    "extra": "🌸"
  },
  {
    "question": "фиолетовый",
    "answer": "fiołietowyj",
    "extra": "🟣"
  },
  {
    "question": "коричневый",
    "answer": "koricznewyj",
    "extra": "🟤"
  },
  {
    "question": "чёрный",
    "answer": "cziornyj",
    "extra": "⚫"
  },
  {
    "question": "белый",
    "answer": "biełyj",
    "extra": "⚪"
  },
  {
    "question": "серый",
    "answer": "sierij",
    "extra": "🔘"
  },
  {
    "question": "голубой",
    "answer": "gołuboj",
    "extra": "🔷"
  },
  {
    "question": "бирюзовый",
    "answer": "birjuzowyj",
    "extra": "🦚"
  },
  {
    "question": "лиловый",
    "answer": "liłowyj",
    "extra": "💜"
  },
  {
    "question": "бежевый",
    "answer": "bieżewyj",
    "extra": "🤎"
  },
  {
    "question": "малиновый",
    "answer": "małinowyj",
    "extra": "🟥"
  },
  {
    "question": "золотой",
    "answer": "zołotoj",
    "extra": "🟨"
  },
  {
    "question": "серебристый",
    "answer": "sierebristyj",
    "extra": "🪙"
  }
];
